# **GRACE BRUNINA**

**UX WRITER** 

#### **DETAILS**

#### **ADDRESS**

Ballston Spa, NY United States

#### PHONE

5182440895

#### **EMAIL**

gracebrunina@gmail.com

#### LINKS

No Stress Self Service Tik

<u>Tok</u>

Elevio Case Study

LinkedIn

### SKILLS

Communication

Teamwork

Leadership

Drive and Initiative

Change Management

**Technology Management** 

Agile

Staff Retention

Clean Writing

Analytical

#### **PROFILE**

A Content Manager with 12 years of experience, looking to transition into a UX Writer role to create more intuitive experiences in-app to reduce the need for technical documentation. Currently managing 7 help centers with an average support deflection rate of 85%.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# **Content Manager, NBC Sports Next**

Remote

2021 - 2023

- Managed 5 content writers remotely, from the Midwest to the UK. Performed weekly 1:1s and promoted continual growth based on Individual Development Plans.
- Analyzed deflection and customer education, and updated content protocols, procedures, and techniques. Currently maintaining a deflection rate between 75-96%.
- Conducted a content governance plan, standardized the content creation processes, and stimulated the team's content quality to 98%.
- Coordinated with 15 product teams to deliver content needs using Agile
   Principals and detailed project documentation averaging a completion of over 1000 stories/tasks per year with 97% satisfaction.

# **Content Team Lead, NBC Sports Next**

2018 — 2021

- Performed continuous improvement activities to ensure content is the end users' first line of defense and the customer support team was working in a "Tier 2" capacity.
- Established open and professional relationships with all department team members ranging from Product to Marketing, to align internal and external users with product training and support.
- Optimized all published content to adhere to brand standards and technical writing methodology.

## **Documentation Specialist, Sports Illustrated Play**

Saratoga Springs

2015 - 2018

- Designed and created the "voice" of straightforward, easy-to-follow and find help/training content. Instituted a style guide to standardize all company materials
- Administered needs assessments to determine content requirements, and optimized articles, guides, and UX copy that dropped support inquiries by 72%.
- Expanded interdepartmental communication which established and maintained relationships with key stakeholders across the organization, resulting in more effective collaboration and efficiency.
- Enhanced the readability of technical documents for a non-technical audience, resulting in a 40% increase in user engagement.

# **Technical Support Team Lead, SportsSignup**

Saratoga Springs

2013 — 2015

- Boosted morale and contributions by 20% while maintaining 100% staff retention during turbulent times by orchestrating and delivering a comprehensive training program, and understanding each individual's goals and drivers.
- Modeled innovative solutions to respond to strategic and organizational needs and enhanced customer satisfaction by 10%.
- Influenced the future of the support team and fostered the change management necessary to succeed by establishing regular meetings to align objectives and strategies with the customer in mind.

# **Technical Support, SportsSignup**

Saratoga Springs

2011 — 2013

- Facilitated technical support to customers over the phone and via email, resulting in a 98% customer satisfaction score.
- Engineered a support center and blog with over 150 articles on common issues, solutions, and tips & tricks, increasing self-service by over 50%.

### EDUCATION

B.A.S. Business and Technology Management, SUNY Delhi

A.A.S Business Administration, Schenectady County Community College